[Music]
It's the Operman Report. Join digital
forensic investigator and PI Ed Operan
for an in-depth discussion of conspiracy
theories, strategy of new world order
resistance, high-profile court cases in
the news, and interviews with expert
guests and authors on these topics and
more. It's the Operman
Report. And now here is investigator Ed
Oppperman.
[Music]
Okay, welcome to the Operman Report. I
am your host, private investigator Ed
Oppperman, and this show is brought to
you by emailrevealer.com.
Uh, you go check out emailrevealer.com.
If you uh need an asset search done or a
locate uh uh well, whatever you want to
catch your spouse cheating online, you
want to trace an email address back to
an online dating service, check out
emailrevealer.com. Uh if this is your
first time listening to this show, uh
you just picked it up on a brand new
station,
uh go to
opermanreport.com and check out our
members section. Uh we have a special
members subscription section uh that uh
it's only for members. Uh we have all
these extra content on there, these
extra shows. Uh this weekend I have a
blockbuster weekend coming up for you um
in the member section. Uh first of all I
have this woman named Millie McGee uh
who wrote a book about Jay Garoover. Uh
incredible stuff. Okay, I'm interviewing
her tomorrow afternoon. Uh then we have
on Sunday uh you everyone who remembers
uh Mayor Jim Rothstein
uh and and loves his uh the shows we did
with him. Uh during the first show, he
recommended that I contact this man
named Robert Merritt. Uh I spoke to
Robert Merritt today and uh he's been a
longtime informant for all different
kinds of government agencies. He's all
mixed up in the Watergate uh case. Uh
this this guy is is one for the the
record books, my friends. Uh but tonight
we have again forget it. Tonight's a
blockbuster show. We have John Kerichu
and uh he is a former CIA agent and he's
the author of The Reluctant Spy and uh
he pretty much just got out of prison uh
for uh being like a whistleblower. Uh so
John, are you there? I sure am. Thanks
for having me. Thank you so much. I'm
really excited to have you on here. Uh
especially the little chat we had off
the air. Uh so give us an idea who is
John Carricku and and what is your
story? Well um I joined the CIA in
January of 1990 as an analyst working on
the Middle East and uh loved that job.
Uh did it for 7 and 1/2 years and then
decided I was ready for something new
and I switched to operations also within
the
CIA and uh did that for another 7 and
1/2 years. So after the September 11th
attacks, I became the chief of CIA uh
counterterrorism operations in Pakistan
and in that capacity led a raid on the
night of March 28th, 2002 that turned
out to be the biggest counterterrorism
raid in CIA history, which still stands.
We captured Abu Zuber, who we believed
at the time was the number three in
al-Qaeda, and we caught 51 other
al-Qaeda fighters. I went home from
Pakistan in uh in late
2002 and was asked when I got home if I
wanted to be certified in the use of
what they called uh enhanced
interrogation techniques. I called them
torture techniques and I declined to be
trained. Uh I left the CIA in 2004, went
into the private sector for a while.
Then I went to the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee and I was the senior
investigator for that committee and I
was the senior intelligence adviser to
the chairman, John Kerry. Uh but in
2007, I went on ABC News and um and I
said three things that really changed
the course of my life. I said that the
CIA was torturing its prisoners. I said
that torture was official US government
policy. And I said that that policy had
been approved and signed by the
president. Now, the president, George W.
Bush, had said earlier in the week with
his eyes right on the camera, he said,
"We do not torture." And I said that the
president is a liar. And so that
resulted in a four-year long uh FBI
investigation. I was finally charged
with five felonies uh including three
counts of espionage for uh saying that
we were torturing prisoners. Uh those
espionage counts were dropped. I took a
plea to a lesser charge. I did 23 months
in a federal prison. Not in a country
club prison, but in a real honest to God
prison. And um and got out this
February.
How old are you now? I'm 51. Just turned
51. Wow. 51. Okay. That's not easy time
going into 30 months in prison. 47. No.
Not not easy time at all. And I'll tell
you what, you know, my only exposure to
prison had been watching MSNBC at 11:00
at night. Um, so I I really didn't know
what to expect and and I thought I was
going to a minimum security work camp.
Uh, that's what the judge had
recommended. That's what the prosecutors
had agreed to. Uh, in fact, the the
Bureau of Prisons does whatever it uh it
pleases. And so, uh, as soon as I
arrived, they they took me around to the
back and put me in the actual prison
rather than in the minimum security
camp. Yeah. Sometimes when I'm watching
Rachel Maddo, I feel like I'm in maximum
security.
Sorry. Can't watch those shows anymore.
Okay. So, you just got out now. Uh, how
old were you when you went into the CIA?
Um, I was young. Let's see. I was 25
when I joined the CIA. And what did you
do before that? Um, I was in grad
school. I I got a bachelor's degree in
in uh Middle Eastern studies. and I was
working on a on a master's degree in
legislative affairs when one of my
professors uh who liked my writing style
uh asked me to stay after class one day
and uh to make a long story short, it
turned out he was actually undercover as
a professor. He was working as what used
to be called a CIA spotter looking for
grad students who would fit into the
agency's culture. And so, um, he
recruited me into the CIA right out of
graduate school.
You know, there must be a lot of that
because I know I've had another I've had
a lot of CIA guys on the show and, uh,
uh, I I believe I've heard that story
before that they were recruited. Yeah.
Yeah. By a professor. Yeah. It it
actually used to be quite common. It it
really, you know, until 1992 or '93 with
the passage of the Equal Employment
Opportunity Act, it was pretty much the
only real way to get into the CIA. You
had to be noticed. You had to be
spotted. I mean, it's like it's like
being at the soda fountain at whatever
that famous uh drugstore was in
Hollywood, you know, if you wanted to be
an actor. So,
um you know, there there used to be
senior CIA officers undercover at
important universities all around the
country and I just, you know, was lucky
enough to to uh have one as my grad
school adviser. Now, so but but you had
no plans uh even though you were taking
these foreign languages. Uh you had no
plans to go into the CIA or something
like that. No, I was thinking that I I
would probably end up on Capitol Hill or
maybe take the foreign service exam. I
knew I wanted to work in foreign affairs
uh doing something, but I hadn't really
given the CIA any thought until they
approached me. Okay, gotcha. Now, now
you said you were at first you were an
analyst or something like that. Yeah, I
was for the first half of my career. And
the the analytic jobs at the CIA are a
lot of fun if especially if you're an
introvert because you're going to sit in
your cubicle 9 or 10 hours a day and
think the big thoughts and write
important papers and send those papers
to the White House and hope that the
president reads them and comments on
them. Um, but you know, after doing that
year in year out, working on Iraq, you
know, year after year after year, it it
wears you down. And I I thought, boy,
I'm I'm 30 years old. There's got to be
more than more to life than this. So,
uh, I decided, you know, I I spoke
Arabic, I spoke Greek, and, um, it was
time for something exciting. And so, on
the strength of those two languages, I
was able to switch over to
counterterrorism operations.
And this is around 30 years old now. So,
you must been in pretty good shape,
right? Yeah, I I was in pretty good
shape. I I wasn't a former military, but
I I was thin and young and strong and
happy to jump out of the plane and be
trained in everything else. And you
know, the friends of mine were like,
"Are you sure you want to do this? This
is going to be rough. This is going to
be like being in the military, at least
through training." And I said, "Yeah, I
know. Yeah, I can I can tough it out for
whatever it was, six or eight months at
the time." And I ended up doing very
well. And I enjoyed it very much. A and
because right because the operations you
were doing as part of the CIA were
actually military combat operations,
right? Well, no. Um they became military
or paramilitary combat operations after
September 11th. Before September 11th,
it was, you know, much more old school.
It was much more sophisticated. Uh where
we have something called the asset
recruitment cycle. It's it's every
officer has to spot, assess, develop,
and recruit um an agent in order to get
promoted, right? You have to recruit
spies to steal secrets. And you spot
these people depending on what your
target is or what kind of job you're
doing at diplomatic cocktail parties or
wherever. I mean, any number of of
different scenarios. After September
11th, it really did change to to
paramilitary operations where, you know,
you're you're wearing whatever special
forces were and you parachute into
something and you shoot the place up and
you grab the bad guy. But before
September 11th, that's really not what
the CIA was. Before it sounds more like
Amway or like you're recruiting people
to come in underneath you, but you know,
pretty much it was the same idea. Then
you have to establish a a relationship
with somebody with your target, right?
You have to establish a rapport um to
the point where you become so close to
that person or at least that person
thinks that you're close. Uh to the
point where he's going to commit
espionage for you, he's going to commit
treason for you because he likes you. I
mean, there's certainly other
motivators, money, revenge, ideology,
but the real basis of the relationship
is friendship. Wow. It's an It's almost
like you're a con man or a cult. You
know, I I've
said years in interviews that that those
of us who were in operations or are in
operations uh right now you're trained
to lie and you lie every day and you lie
all day and you live a lie. You just
have to know when to turn it off at the
end of the day. A lot of guys can't and
so you know the CIA has a skyhigh
divorce rate. Um but uh yeah you you are
very well trained as a professional
liar. Okay. Fascinating. Okay. So now uh
and you said that you you went you went
to Afghanistan and you captured this
guy. Who was this guy you captured in in
Pakistan? This was Abu Zabeda. We
thought at the time that he was the
number three in al-Qaeda. Okay. In fact,
he had never actually joined al-Qaeda,
but his job was to provide al-Qaeda's um
logistical support, logistical
leadership. He created al-Qaeda's two
training camps in southern Afghanistan.
Um if you needed a false passport or you
needed a plane ticket, Abu Zuba was the
guy. If you needed a safe house or a way
to uh to get from point A to point B
across the border, you went to Abu Zuba.
So although he had never formally joined
al-Qaeda, he had never pledged feely to
Osama bin Laden, he was al-Qaeda's go-to
guy for logistics.
Okay, that's interesting. So now, but
you hear these stories over here in the
United States that they're hanging out
in caves and stuff like that. Yeah, not
true. Okay, then give us I don't I don't
know how that rumor ever got started
that they were living in caves. That the
whole cave story never made sense to me
because I mean these guys are just like
everybody else. You can you can rough it
for for only so long. You know, people
used to ask me, "Where do you think Bin
Laden is?" And I said, I used to say, "I
think Bin Laden is comfortable in a
house in a major city somewhere." And
I'll tell you why. Because these guys
always thought that we thought that they
were hiding in the tribal areas because
we can't get to the tribal areas except
with the use of drones. In fact, we knew
that they were all in major cities. And
it was this reverse reverse psychology.
So when they're in the cities thinking
that we're looking for them in the
countryside, they tend to be a little
bit more sloppy, especially with their
electronic communications, cell phones,
email, stuff like that. And then they're
easier to catch when they're in the
city. I mean, we caught Abu Zuba in a
major city. We caught Khaled Shikh
Muhammad in a major city. He was the
mastermind of the 911 attacks. We caught
uh Abdulahanidi in a major city. He was
the mastermind of the coal bombing. We
caught Ramsey Binib in a major city. And
then of course, you know, Bin Laden was
in the Pakistani version of West Point
in a major city. Yeah. Right. Now, now
what do you make of that? You know, cuz
uh you'd think that these guys would be
on our side, right? Or on your side, you
know, on the CIA side. Oh well, you
know, I always said that the Pakistani
Intelligence Service, ISI, was really
two separate organizations. The the guys
that I was working with were were just
fantastic. I mean, they were all trained
in the UK. Uh they all went through
Sandhurst and British police training
and they were really great. They were
great counterterrorism partners. But ISI
is also the same organization that
created the Taliban. You know when when
Benazir Bhau was the prime minister of
Pakistan, she created the Taliban. See
Taliban is a word in both Arabic and in
Udu that means uh students. The the the
singular is Talib and the plural is
Taliban which means students. And these
students were studying in Madras in
Islamic private Islamic schools in
Pakistan. And they were they were Afghan
nationals. So the Pakistanis were
running trucks across Afghanistan to
Iran so that they could sell their goods
in Iran and the um trucks were being
hijacked as they were crossing Pakistan.
So Benazir BH got this group of students
together and said I want you to ride
along in the trucks you know with
weapons and if anybody tries to hijack
the trucks fight them off. So as these
trucks would cross Afghanistan, the
Taliban were able to secure individual
uh villages along the route and that's
how they ended up taking over Pakistan.
So Benazer Bhau and ISI created the
Taliban, they trained the Taliban, they
financed the Taliban, they armed the
Taliban and at the same time other ISI
officers are working with us to fight
the Taliban. So there was this
disconnect within the Pakistani
intelligence service. You could trust
some of them, you couldn't trust others.
You just had to play your cards well.
Okay. Now, I I recall I forget who was
president at the time, but I I recall
the Taliban coming to the United States
and it was like a big press conference
and it was revealed that their lobbyist
was the daughter of one of the CIA
directors. Are you familiar with that
story?
Yeah, I do remember that story. And I I
recall she was based in New Jersey, I
think it was. Do you remember which CI
CIA director that was? Yeah, I don't.
But I I recall it being sort of a
non-controversial issue at the time
because, you know, we we never had any
beef with the Taliban historically. that
some of those members of the Taliban,
especially the older ones, were jihadis
from the from the uh the war against the
Soviets. And of course, we we financed
them, we trained them, we armed them, we
gave them Stinger missiles, and every
year or two, they would come to the
United States, they would meet with
President Reagan, they would be fetted
in Washington, then they'd go back to uh
to Afghanistan. So, we had this
relationship with at least some of these
these people. And until bin Laden went
to
Afghanistan, we sort of saw the Taliban
as not our fight. If if they were going
to trample women's rights, well, you
know, we had no national interest there.
It was none of our business. It wasn't
until they provided safe haven for Bin
Laden that we decided this was going to
be a problem.
What do you make of Bin Laden? Okay.
There's some people say that outright
that he was CIA and they had I think his
name was Osman or something like that.
Ben Osman, you know, they had another
name, you know. Yeah. And that
uh and then you got all this stuff about
how um his brothers connected up with
the the Carile group and was actually
meeting with Bush the the day of 9/11.
Oh. Oh, sure. But but that's not
scandalous. That's not unusual. First of
all, Bin Laden was never trained by the
CIA. He was never a CIA source. He was
never armed by the CIA. He didn't
actually go to Afghanistan from Saudi
Arabia until after the CIA um stopped
funding and training uh the uh Afghan
mujaheden. So that's kind of a common
misnomer. A lot of people think that the
CIA trained Bin Laden or created bin
Laden. That's just not true. Um you're
talking about the extended Bin Laden
family. The Bin Laden family is a very
honorable family in Saudi Arabia.
They're incredibly wealthy, you know, 10
figure kind of wealthy because the old
man Abdul Rahman bin Laden who
originally moved to Saudi Arabia from
Yemen um created what became the
kingdom's largest construction firm and
and his firm would make would would do
the biggest projects. They would build
airports and and hospitals and ports and
shopping malls and stuff like that.
So, old the old man insisted that that
most if not all of his uh children be
educated in the West. Um they travel to
the United States all the time. They own
property in Beverly Hills and in Miami
Beach. And you know, they're very
Americanized. It's just that that one
son, Osama, was for whatever reason
radicalized. and instead of going into
the family business along with his 113
other brothers,
um he he went to Afghanistan to make
jihad.
And and and what do you make of uh
people who say, "Well, he he died prior
to the to the story that that we hear in
the news about him." Yeah, that that's
just nonsense. I mean, you know, we we
would get these reports at the CIA all
the time that Bin Laden had kidney
failure. He was on dialysis inside a
cave. uh he had u some kind of spinal
disorder. We were always getting these
these uh medical uh rumors reported back
to us and and none of them ended up uh
to be true. But no, he he he was in
perfectly fine health except for some
arthritis. Um he had an ongoing hip
problem. Um but he he was he was healthy
enough to wage war against the United
States until the day he died.
Okay.
Um, oh boy. Oh, okay. I almost forgot.
Okay, set my mind for a second. What
What do you make of these stories about
the the the Navy Seals uh who are part
of that operation now all of a sudden
they're all dead in uh in helicopter
crashes and stuff, right? You know,
that's actually not uncommon. Um being a
Navy Seal is one of the most dangerous
professions in the world. And um we're
not talking specifically about the Navy
Seals who were directly uh involved in
the Bin Laden takedown being killed.
We're talking about Navy Seals from
their broader unit. So we're talking
about, you know, 100, 120, 150 SEALs. So
for for a number of SEALs, a high number
of SEALs to be killed, um whether it's
in accidents or in combat is actually
very sadly uh common.
Okay. Okay. So, no, so you're saying
that the uh when we hear these stories
about how the Navy Seals who killed Bin
Laden, now most of them are dead. It's
You're saying it's not the actual same
guys. It's just the guys in the same No,
not at all. Okay. It's not the same
guys. Uh-uh. Interesting.
Okay. Um Yeah, let me interrupt you. You
know, when when people talk about Seal
Team Six, um or you see Steel Team Six
in movies, you you imagine a dozen or
dozen half guys that make up Seal Team
Six. In fact, it's several hundred guys
that make up Seal Team Six. And it's,
you know, from those several hundred uh
that that we find these these
individuals who have been killed in
accidents or killed in combat. Now, what
about the stories about the the funeral
like this this ocean funeral and then
even some uh congressmen who saw
pictures and stuff like that said it
looked like it was fake and and then
even the White House had to kind of step
back on some of the official story
around that. What do you make of that?
Yeah, you know, I don't know what to
believe. I I think he probably was
buried at sea the way they they say he
was buried at sea. Maybe some of the
details are wrong cuz God knows the
White House's story changes constantly
uh every time this comes up. But I I
don't I just don't see any conspiracy
related to it.
I see a bunch of people talking out of
school and and pretending to know the
details of what happened when in fact
they don't really know the details. And
I think that's why the story tends to
change. But I do think that Bin Laden
was killed uh in whatever it was, May of
2011. I think he really was buried at
sea. Um and I I'm just not sure that the
details are really that important. Now,
now how about when you were in CIA, were
you ever involved in like promoting
false stories and and uh No, you know, I
there there is such a thing as a false
flag operation. False flag operations
are very very um difficult and there are
a lot of moving parts and you have to
have a lot of people that buy into the
conspiracy. Um but but we really didn't
use those very often because they were
so complicated. It wasn't until, you
know, just
recently, you know, where people have
started to email me or Facebook me or
contact me on Twitter about false flag
operations. And you I I even have one
friend who just thinks that every event
in life is a false flag operation. And
it's just it just seems so preposterous
to me because they are so labor
intensive and so difficult to carry out.
That just doesn't make sense to me.
Yeah. I I sympathize with you. I get
those emails, too.
They mean well. I They really do. But I
know. And you kind of can't blame some
people for being paranoid, you know. You
can't blame people for being paranoid.
No, you can't. You know, when when you
have a government that's not
transparent, right? When you have a
government that that pretends to tell
the American people the whole story uh
related to these to these terrorist uh
you know, operations. And then the story
changes. You can't blame people for
being for being suspicious of the
government line. Right. Right. And and
you said now we have a government that
tortures people and says it's okay.
Exactly. And that denied it and denied
it and denied it. You know, I said this
I said this the other day in in an op-ed
that I wrote. Everything that the
government has told us about torture
since 2002 has been a lie. So why would
you believe them? Now, you know, George
W. Bush said in 2002, "We don't
torture." And he said it again in three
and four and five and six and seven. The
week that I went on ABC News, he looked
right in the camera and he said, "We do
not torture." And I remember saying to
my wife, "That is a bald-faced lie. He's
just lying to the American people." And
George Tennant said the same thing in
2005 on 60 Minutes. He came off in that
segment like he was unhinged. He was
practically shouting it. We don't
torture. We don't torture. We don't
torture. Well, of course we
torture. And what makes it worse is not
only are there US laws that that
prohibit
torture, but there are international
treaties and conventions that the US is
a signatory to and in some cases that
the US wrote and bullied other countries
into signing. And then we violate those
international treaties and conventions
by torture. Let me tell you another
thing. In January of 1968, the
Washington Post ran a front page
photograph of a of an American soldier
waterboarding a North Vietnamese
prisoner. When that photo was published,
the Secretary of Defense, Robert
McNamera, um ordered an investigation.
The soldier was arrested and he was
charged with torture and he was
convicted and sent to prison. So why was
torture illegal in 1968, but it wasn't
illegal in 2002? Cuz the law didn't
change. There was no there was no
amendment to the law banning torture,
saying, "Well, okay, now it's okay." You
know, there was no law that said, "Well,
water boarding is not torture. Cold
cell's not torture. sleep deprivation,
not torture. The law didn't change, but
we just had a group of attorneys in the
Justice Department who decided that they
were going to twist the law uh to do
what they wanted and that's exactly what
happened. Yeah, this is really, you
know, you and I are the same age, you
know, uh and this it this is such a a
disturbing uh that even that we're even
talking about this and that people are
excusing it and uh it's really uh
shattering. It is. It is. You know, I I
I consider myself to be a patriot. And
not just a patriot, but a patriot who
who spent 20 years serving my country in
some of the most awful and dangerous
places on earth. And I know that my
country is better than this. My country
shouldn't be waterboarding people or or
forcing hummus up their rectums or
murdering them in the middle of of uh
interrogations or to make matters worse
droning American citizens overseas who
have not been charged with a crime who
have not had the right to meet their
accusers in court. That's not the
America that I know and love. I don't
know where this came from. Okay. Okay.
Well, then then coming from where you
are right now today and and just having
served 30 months, I believe, right? 30
months. Yes. Do you still consider
yourself a patriot? Do you still support
the Iraq war, the the Afghanistan war?
Do you still uh where are you now? Well,
I I am a patriot. I never I never
supported the Iraq war, though. I never
thought that was a just war. And I even
spent a good amount of uh space in my in
my first book about it. U that was a war
of choice. That was a war of revenge for
the Bush family. Uh but yeah, I I always
supported the Afghan war. I don't
anymore because because the the whole
point of the Afghan war was to defeat
al-Qaeda and we defeated al-Qaeda by the
middle of 2003. So the rest of this
since 2003, this has been nation
building which is never a good idea. But
yeah, I I am still a patriot and I want
my September 10th country back. And what
about the overthrow ruined by by George
W. Bush and by Barack Obama equally?
What about the overthrow in Libya?
See, this is another thing. Gaddafi was
a was a very bad guy, but we actually
had a very healthy working relationship
with with Gaddafi. And Gaddafi hated
al-Qaeda as much as we did. So, flipping
sides at the last minute like we did to
overthrow Gaddafi was a was a terrible
policy error. I mean, look at the place
now. It's it's literally anarchy. It's
chaos. Right. Well, you say it's a
policy area, but according to Wesley
Clark, he says that's the plan all along
is to cause destabilization to cause
chaos. See, this is the thing. And and
Wes Clark, I mean, Wes Clark was a
four-star general, um, he ought to know
um, what he's talking about. So, if
that's if that's the policy, I think
that's an incredibly shortsighted policy
because invariably where there's a power
vacuum, we get dragged in. And when we
get dragged into something like this,
like we did in Lebanon, for example, in
the 1980s, we can't get ourselves back
out again. Do do you think there's a
motive to get us back out when the when
these companies like Hallebertton are
making all this money on laundry and and
it just it's unbelievable the kind of
money they're making over there? That
that's a really important point. I never
believed that until I'm going to say the
last four or five years. And I I've come
to the conclusion that that we need
economically we need for war to be a
permanent thing. Yeah. And already the
American people are sort of numb to the
idea of war in part because we have an
allv volunteer military. Uh and I think
that's why we're not seeing
demonstrations in the streets. I mean
already Afghanistan it's the longest war
in American history. It's twice as long,
more than actually it's more than Well,
now it's it's three times as long as
World War II was. And uh you know,
nobody's really upset about this.
Yeah, we better take a commercial break.
Uh we're here with uh John in Kuraku.
Kuraku. Karaku. John Kuraku. He's the
author of Reluctant Spy. Uh I have it
right here. uh American no reluctant spy
my secret life in the CIA's war on
terror and I have a link to that uh book
the Amazon link on the
operanreportblogspot.com and it'll be in
the oper uh bookstore. Uh but John
what's your website? Oh it's uh
www.jhcuryaku.com. So it's
jn k i r i a
ko.com. We'll be right back with more of
John Kiryaku right after these
messages. And now, a word from our
sponsors. Pacific West Bamboo, your
premier source for sustainable building
material. They provide construction
grade and craft grade bamboo material
for all your indoor, outdoor, and
gardening needs. Uh, contact them for
event planning and display building as
well.
5038398126 or you go to their new
website pacific
westbamboo.com or you can contact them
on Facebook at Pacific Westbamboo.
That's
5038398126. Amanda from Pacific West
Bamboo was our first sponsor. Uh she's
been so good to us. Uh so please support
her in return. I want to make everybody
aware of our new member section at
www.opermanreport.com.
operandreport.com. Uh you can go there
and sign up for a monthly, quarterly, or
yearly
subscription. You can even purchase
episodes one by one. Uh you get full
access to brand new original content,
new guests, new uncensored interviews,
my own investigations and reports, and
we're going to be adding uh sections
with documents, images, police reports
uh either provided by myself or by my
guests or for my own investigations, my
own reports. Uh, so you can go to
operandreport.com and you can sign up
there tonight. You can start listening
tonight. Straw Man, I want to mention
Straw Man. Straw Man is a band uh out of
Toronto, Canada. Uh, they're good
friends at the Operant Report. Uh,
they're a trio of guys who share the
same mindset uh most of us here do, and
they put that energy into their words
and music. Uh, so check them out at
strawmanmusic.com and drop him a line uh
to let him know that you heard him here
on the Arkman Report. Uh, we'll be doing
an interview with Shawn Duffy
soon. You can get an autographed copy of
my book, How to Succeed as a Private
Investigator, by visiting my PI website,
email
revealer.com. We also offer a computer
and cell phone forensics. We can recover
deleted text messages to uncover
infidelity. Uh we can uh we offer asset
searches, locates, email tracing,
background reports, and we can even
trace your spouse's email address back
to internet dating websites to catch
them cheating online. You can reach us
at
800572-9762 or you can email me at email
revealerol.com. New World Mexican Women.
Everyone loves the New World Mexican
women and their their line of fine
handcrafted authentic Mexican jewelry of
stone mosaic and abilain stone inlay. In
their first book titled New World
Mexican Women, available on lulu.com, uh
they teach you how to make this jewelry
and they have a collection of love
letters to their men from their hometown
that have immigrated to the United
States to find work. Uh they have also
published a new book entitled Azucina to
the rodeo. It's about a young girl that
falls in love with a rodeo bull rider
and she runs away with him uh without
telling her family. You can find the New
World Mexican women by googling New
World Mexican women. And you can ask
them about uh their deals on
wholesaling, their fine jewelry, and all
of the other projects that they have
going on. Uh if you'd like to have your
business or website advertised here and
promoted all over the world on dozens of
stations every day, give us a call at
8005729762 or email
opermanreportgmail.com. And now back to
our
show. Okay, welcome back to the Operman
Report. I'm your host, private
investigator Ed Aberman. Uh we're here
tonight with John Kiryaku, uh who's the
author of Reluctant Spy. Uh real quick,
I want to give a shout out to John
Podash. Uh John Podash, a really big
friend of the show here. He's the author
of uh Drugs as a Weapon Against Us. Uh
and that's the the FBI's war on Tupac.
Uh he's going to be doing a slideshow
presentation at Loo De Jesus uh in
California. Now, this is this weekend
from 4:00 to 7:00 p.m. Sunday night uh
on 10:25 on Hollywood Boulevard and then
again on uh Esso Juan Books
uh on
10:28 from 7 to 8:30 p.m. and that's off
Cshaw Boulevard and Lamont Park. Uh so
uh if you need some direction, you can
just email me at operreport.com and I'll
get a holding for you. Um, but we are
here
tonight with John Kuryaku, reluctant
spy, my secret life in the CIA's war on
terror. So, now John, where did
um the torturing get started? Was this
at the Guantanamo? Was this in Abu Grae?
Where did you It was before Abu Grae and
um actually before Guantanamo. uh Abis
Ba was the first highlevel
uh al-Qaeda related prisoner that we had
captured. And
so you know at the time and when I say
at the time I mean I mean immediately
after the September 11th attacks, Osama
bin Laden released a statement in which
he said that al-Qaeda was planning
another attack that would dwarf
September 11th. And we were panicked at
the thought because September 11th was a
was a disaster. It was an intelligence
failure. It was just an an
acrosstheboard, you know, American
failure. So we were worried about this
this what they call the ticking time
bomb
scenario. And
so CIA's leadership believed that Abda
had information related to whatever this
upcoming attack was or was going to be.
In fact, there there was no upcoming
attack. Uh he just said it to panic us
and and he
succeeded. So, a decision was made at
CIA headquarters that we were going to
come up with these with these torture
techniques. It was a list of of
something like 10 different torture
techniques. And um and they sent this
list to the Justice Department, which
approved it. And then it went to the
lawyers at the National Security
Council. They approved it. From there it
went to the um national security adviser
who was she was conda race at the time.
She approved it and sent it to the
president. Well, nobody in the CIA's
leadership thought the president was
going to approve this cuz it was clearly
torture. And sure enough, he approved
it. And I remember sitting in a meeting
with the deputy director of the CIA um
the day after the memo, the signed memo
came into headquarters and the deputy
director said something like three times
during the course of our conversation, I
can't believe the president signed that
memo. I can't believe it. And that's how
the torture regime started.
Guantanamo I mean we we really didn't
even how should I say this? Guantanamo
was supposed to be a temporary stop.
See, we were we were capturing people so
quickly and we were capturing so many of
them, especially after the fall of Tora
Bora in October 2001, that we needed
someplace to just park them long enough
uh for us to put all the paperwork
together and then send them to the
United States to stand trial because
September 11th was still an ongoing open
criminal investigation. Guantanamo was
never supposed to be permanent. They
were supposed to stay there only long
enough for us to then send them onward
to the states for uh for trial. And of
course, nobody ever went on trial. And
here we are 14 years later and we're
still talking about whether or not we
should close Guantanamo.
You know, my next guest tonight, uh,
Michael, uh, Bo, the attorney, uh, and
the story is about how the Marines
turned a blind eye to child sex abuse.
Did you ever run in across any of that
over there? Yeah, in Afghanistan, you
actually run into it with some
regularity. It's this weird thing in
Afghan culture that if a boy um does not
yet have whiskers, if he hasn't yet
reached puberty, um you can have sex
with him. Uh it's specific to to um
Sunni Muslims. And uh that's why a lot
of a lot of Taliban uh would would rape
young boys. It's just this weird
perverted cultural thing that they have.
What about the stories we heard of of uh
young boys being raped at Abu Grae in
front of their parents as part of
interrogation?
Um to the best of my understanding that
didn't happen. Although I mean it's
almost as bad. Uh it's my understanding
that some of our soldiers threatened
prisoners with that. That if you don't
talk we're going to rape your children.
if you don't talk, we're gonna rape your
your wife or we're gonna rape rape your
children in front of your wife. We'll
rape your wife in front of you. You
know, that kind of thing. Now, that
that's also a violation of law, both US
law and and uh the um United Nations
Convention on Torture. Uh but we we
actually did that kind of thing in Abu
Grave, at least threatened it. I mean,
well, if you look at some of the
pictures that came out of Abu, have you
been to Abu Grae? What do you know
firstand? No. No, I've not been to have
a grape. Okay. But you you've seen some
of those pictures that came out of
there. Oh, yeah. They're horrific. Naked
guys and naked guys in a pyramid. You
know that it's way beyond the naked guys
with electrical wires attached to their
scrotums. You know, we we did horrible
things to people over there. So,
whatever things that that aren't that
aren't appropriate in any circumstance,
whether in war or peace or even
effective to get uh confessions out of
people. And really, that's the most
important point. They're not effective
in any way in getting confessions or in
getting any kind of intelligence. You
know, we know now from both the Senate
torture report and the CIA Inspector
General's report that was released in
the spring of 2009 that torture never
worked, that that CIA interrogators
never gathered any actionable
intelligence and that no American lives
were saved. And and let me add one more
thing about that, too. You hear a lot of
people now saying, "Well, it was just
the Senate Intelligence Committee
Democrats that signed on to that
report." Let me remind those naysayers
that the Senate Democrats and the Senate
Intelligence Committee investigators
used primary source documents, that is
original CIA intelligence cables from
the field to write that report. So there
is no rebuttal. You know, there is no
excuse. Torture didn't work. It never
works. It didn't save any American
lives.
Did you watch the hearings yesterday? I
did. Okay. So did I. The whole thing all
day long. Now, now, what do you make of
that? It seems to me that something more
was going on down there with the CIA
compound across from this uh you know,
you've heard the rumors, right, about
gun running and these kind of things.
What do you make of that? Yeah, I think
there's actually uh some evidence of gun
running.
Yeah, you know, this this whole idea of
gununn um has been a problem really
since the very beginning of the uprising
against
Gaddafi already already Libya is kind of
a no man's land because it's its borders
aren't clearly defined. The desert is
constantly shifting. Libya is an
intensely tribally based society. So,
you can't really, you know, people in
Libya never really trust their central
government. And then you've got vast
numbers of weapons uh changing hands.
So, you know, who's involved? I'm not
sure we're ever going to really get to
the bottom of that story. Was the CIA
involved? Were the British involved?
Were the Egyptians involved? I don't
think we'll ever really know.
And it doesn't seem like that these
hearings are even trying to find out.
Yeah. you know, there are so many
legitimate issues that we could be
talking about related to Benghazi or or
Libya more broadly. Um, and instead it
just devolves into this this political
thing between Hillary Clinton and the
Republicans on the committee. I don't
think anybody did the American people
any service by allowing this to become
political when there are some very
important intelligence issues at play
here. And you know, I I saw a thing on
the news the other day saying that in
the years that George W. Bush was was uh
uh president, something like 60 attacks,
there were 60 attacks around the world
against American embassies and
consulates, including I forget what, you
know, half a dozen or a dozen deaths.
And we've never investigated any of
those. Maybe we should maybe we should
investigate every time there's an attack
on a on an American embassy or consulate
or anytime American personnel overseas
are killed. It shouldn't be political.
It shouldn't be partisan. It should be
something we're doing so that we can
improve the protection of our own
facilities and our own people. Yeah.
There were half a dozen embassy attacks
that weekend. It was demonstrations, but
they breached the region. Yeah. So,
yeah. Why aren't we why aren't we
investigating that? Well, yeah, good
question. You know, it's a circus.
That's why. Look at Donald Trump. We got
We got all of that. It's a circus over
there right now, man. That's right. I
wish you would torture me. I wish you I
can't take any more of this. What do you
make of uh we just had this thing in the
news just in the past week where this
guy this uh Fox News commentator was
claiming to be a CIA. What's going on
with that, man? You know, it's funny to
me. I have run into so many people over
the years who claim to be agency, right?
And um and you can spot them from a mile
away because they they get the lingo
wrong. Uh I I interviewed a guy one
time. He I was working in the private
sector after I left the CIA and I was
working um in competitive intelligence,
business intelligence. And so this guy
applied for a job and and on his resume
he said he was a CIA officer. And I
thought, "Oh, okay. Well, I'm going to
I'm going to take this guy to lunch and
uh you know, maybe we have some friends
in common. I'll see if he's any good."
So I took him to lunch and I said to
him, "Listen," I said, "It's it's not
clear from your resume whether you were
from the Director of Operations or the
Director of Intelligence." Uh, so where
did you work? And he said, 'Oh, both. I
was I was both. And I said, 'Well,
that's kind of impossible. You have to
be from one or the other. Oh. He says, I
was operations. I said, oh, okay. Uh, so
where did you work? He said, oh, I was
counterterrorism. I said, well, that's
great. I was counterterrorism. What
division were you in? And he just looked
at me with this blank this blank.
And I said, you made all this up, didn't
you? and he's like, "I'm really sorry. I
really need this job." And I said,
"Okay, thanks. Nice meeting you." And
that was the end of it. So, this guy on
Fox News, you know, he said he was a
something like outside paramilitary
special operations. Well, those are just
meaningless words. There is no such
position as outside paramilitary special
operations. I mean, it it sounds like
very woo, very intriguing, and it's it's
all these buzzwords, but it but it
doesn't mean anything. There is no such
position. And so, you know, the first
time I heard this guy say, I thought,
absolutely no way he's CIA. He may have
been a contractor. You know, he may have
been inflating what he did, but there's
no way this guy was CIA. And then sure
enough, he wasn't.
Okay. But now, first, how do you get
away with that?
You know, it's why doesn't the CIA step
right away and say, "This guy's not the
he's not the real deal." Yeah. He's not
the real deal. The the real shame about
this whole thing is that apparently this
son of a gun was able to trick people at
at DoD into giving him a security
clearance. Yeah. Just because he told
them he had been CIA. This guy went
overseas to Afghanistan to advise our
generals on strategy because he said he
was from the CIA. Well, I can tell you
any CIA officer I've ever worked with
could peg this guy in 5 seconds and say,
"This guy's making the whole thing up."
Well, okay. You know, we spend a lot of
money to support the CIA, right? Yeah.
Do they have TV sets?
Do they have cable news? Couldn't they
turn on their TV over there and see this
guy on TV and say, "Hey, does anybody
know this guy?" Yeah. And we all do
that, right? Like every once in a while,
if I'm flipping through Fox News, I'll
see somebody like, well, I won't even
say his name, but I'll see somebody I I
served with and I'm like, "Oh, hey, he
ended up on Fox News. Good for him." Or
else I saw I saw a former mine on CNBC
and I was like, "Oh, hey, there's Mike.
He's on CNBC. Good for Mike." But this
guy, I mean, you would think that
somebody would say, you know, gez, I'm
paramilitary at CIA. I never saw this
guy before. Or or even active duty right
now, CIA would they must be checking to
see what information slipping out
through Fox News or through the news.
You would think. Yeah. Yeah. You would
think I I would have You're You're
exactly right. I would have expected
somebody at the CIA to call Fox News and
say, "Hey, this guy's an impostor." And
especially when we know for a fact that
the intelligence uh departments have a
lot of control over what goes on in the
media and the news and movies.
Absolutely. Yeah. I got some guys here.
I'm working with Pierce Redmond and Tom
Secker. They they they get the FOIA
records of how the military and the
defense department is so involved in the
movie industry. It's into such detail
you wouldn't believe. Yeah. It's
embarrassing even. Yeah. So now, how did
this guy get away with this for so long?
I I don't know. It's I I hope that this
is an anomaly. No, it's not. I hope that
somehow, for whatever reason, this guy
slipped through the cracks. I will add
though that his message on Fox News was
always solidly pro-CIA, solidly prodd.
And I wonder if people at the CIA did
know that he was an impostor, but
figured, well, you know, he's saying all
the right things, so we're not going to
object.
Okay. Yeah. Because because I, you know,
in my business, I run into a lot of
these guys who make these kind of
claims. In my business as a PI and also
as radio hosts, I run into these
crackpots all day long. you know, some
of them are radio hosts, and I don't
understand how uh they're getting away
with this. I worked with a guy in the
private sector who I I never met anybody
who so desperately wanted to be a CIA
officer as this guy. And so, he finally
got himself u in as a contractor. And I
said to him, "So, what are you doing
over there anyway?" And he says, "Well,
uh, it's it's it's pretty hush- hush,
but it's special intel ops, uh, support,
uh, special weapons and tactics." And
and I'm like, "Dude, you make yourself
sound like a fool." Yeah, because none
of those words mean
anything. And you get that a lot,
especially in Washington. It's pretty
sad. Yeah, I hear you. I hear you.
People, they try and talk his lingo, but
you know, it's just the boots on the
ground, you know. Exactly. all the
buzzwords and the and the catchphrases.
Oh man.
You know, listen, we're down to like the
last nine minutes, you know. What do you
want to leave us with? Give us some
advice here.
Well, one thing that I'm really that I'm
really upset about uh since September
11th and and this is something that I I
write about a lot and I take very
seriously and it's the loss of our civil
liberties, the civil liberties of
individual Americans in the name of
national
security. When I first uh joined the
CIA, we had several rules that were
written in stone. And that was that the
CIA did not spy on Americans and that's
the NSA did not spy on Americans. And
if, for example, if the NSA had
accidentally stumbled onto an American
or had accidentally
um intercepted a telephone
call, every trace of that interception
had to be purged from NSA's records. And
then NSA had to inform Congress, oh my
god, we've accidentally intercepted the
phone call or the email of an American
citizen. Well, now NSA's primary targets
are American
citizens. NSA just built a a a new
facility in the desert in Utah that has
enough storage space to save every phone
call, every text message, and every
email from every American for the next
500 years.
We have the CIA droning American
citizens overseas, as I said earlier,
who have never been charged with a
crime, who have never been able to face
their accusers in a court of law. And uh
and there just doesn't seem to be any
outrage over this. If if the the
government can kill uh you know, an
American citizen overseas, then can the
government kill an American citizen, you
know, on his ranch in Idaho?
I we don't know and the attorney general
of the United States at least the the
previous one uh Eric Holder wouldn't
even answer that question when when
asked it by uh Senator Rand Paul. So I'm
just seeing a real devolution in our
civil liberties and uh I think it's a
very u dangerous uh trend. Yeah. And the
government whether or not they they
they're killing people, you know, off
the street and they they definitely are
throwing people in prison off the
street. Yeah, they sure are. I mean, you
can testify firsthand. And I got to tell
you, a good number of my guests on this
show have been in prison, you know, uh
and it just seems to be a recurring uh I
got former guests that are in prison
right now, you know, for for nonsense.
Again, liberty kind of stuff, you know.
Yeah. Yeah. Good grief. I'll tell you, I
was charged under the Espionage Act
because I had a conversation with a with
a reporter from the New York Times and I
said that we were torturing prisoners.
So, that bought me three espionage
counts. Um, the Espionage Act was
written in 1917 to target German
saboturs during the First World War.
Between 1917 and 2009, it was used three
times. But since Barack Obama became
president, it's been used nine times
against Americans. Now, none of us none
of us have been accused of of passing
information to a foreign government, to
an enemy. These were all for um
information that uh that went to the
press. And for several of us, and I'm
thinking about, you know, myself and Tom
Drake, for example, from NSA and Jeffrey
Sterling from CIA, it was after we had
either reported through the chain of
command or gone public with evidence of
waste, fraud, abuse, illegality, or
threat to public health or safety.
That's the definition of whistleblowing.
So, here we are near the end of Barack
Obama's uh second uh second term. And I
can safely say, I think that Barack
Obama is going to go down in history as
the enemy of transparency, as the enemy
of of whistleblowing and of transparent
government. And that's exactly what he
said he would not do when elected
president. Okay, that's a good question.
What do you make of Barack Obama?
because a lot of people I've had on this
show that have met him, okay, like
Cynthy McKenna and Cindy Shehan and
others, uh, including a former State
Department guy who's a K Street lobbyist
right now, okay? Uh, and when I asked
them this question, you know, cuz his
obviously his paperwork and his
background is suspect. He doesn't have
the right paperwork, do you make him to
be a
CIA creation?
[Applause]
I've been very public with my opinion on
this and and I'll tell you what I think
has happened.
you had a a very junior senator, a very
junior firstterm senator who had no
exposure to national security, uh no
experience in national security at all,
that's exactly the kind of young new
president the CIA wants because as soon
as that new president sees his first
blue border report or black border
report, something that's so many levels
above top secret they can't even keep
track, as soon as he's brought into his
first super secret
operation. They have him hooked and
they've essentially recruited him. And I
think that that is exactly what happened
to Barack Obama. You know, he campaigned
as an outsider. He came camp campaigned
on the idea of of clean government and
transparency. And as soon as they
brought him into the club, they had him.
There was a book that came out in
2014 by Halpern and Halman uh two
reporters uh Time magazine and MSNBC.
They had done a report or they had done
a book rather on the 2008 election and
then they did a follow-up book on the
2012 election. And there were two quotes
from Barack Obama in that second book
that were really chilling. And Obama had
agreed to uh to an interview for the
book. So these came right from the
horse's mouth. First, he said, "I never
told anybody I was a liberal." And I
thought that was just fascinating. The
second quote was, "I never had any idea
I would be so good at killing people."
And with that, he was talking about the
drone program. And
and that tells me that that's not how he
went into his
presidency. It's how he changed once he
became president.
That's very interesting. But, uh, I had
a guest on here that discussed some of
his previous employment and, uh, he
described it as a a classic CIA front
operation.
Yeah. But the CIA doesn't do stuff like
that. I mean, they they just that's
that's the stuff of movies and fiction
books. That's just not how it works.
Okay. And and and the history with his
parents and stuff like that and their
travels and associations with communists
and all that. You don't see anything
suspect with that either? No, I don't. I
mean, you're talking about about a plot
that would have
begun with with his birth. I mean, I I
don't know anybody that's that smart or
that's that good to be able to carry out
this conspiracy from from the guy's
birth all the way to the presidency,
like a Manurion candidate.
Gotcha. Okay. I I really want to have
you back um to to discuss the whole
story of Abu Grae, you know, and all
that kind of stuff just just
specifically to get into all the details
on that just uh uh 100% specifically.
But once again, what's your your
website? Oh, thanks. My website is uh
www.jhuryaku.com. It's John Jhn. Kuryaku
is k i r i a ko.com.
And we got the book Reluctant Spy: My
Secret Life in the CIA's War on Terror.
Uh but you got a couple other books
you're working on too as well. Yeah. Um
I've got two books completed that are
out for bid right now. One is called
Letters from Lorettto. Uh which um is
based on a series of blogs that I wrote
from prison. And uh the second one or
it's the third one, I guess. Um it's
more fun. It's it's called Doing Time
Like a Spy. How the CIA taught me to
survive and thrive in Prison. Okay,
listen. You got to promise me you're
gonna come back. All right. I'd love to.
Thanks for having Hey, man. That's good
stuff. We got to get into that. Uh but
uh John couldn't stay late tonight. He
couldn't give me two hours because his
kids are are uh his wife's out of town,
so he's babysitting the kids and so he
he didn't know he'd be able to give me
that much time. But thank you so much
for coming on, my friend. Oh, it's my
pleasure. Thanks a lot. Good night.
Bye-bye. Okay, John Kiryaku. Great guy.
Now we have coming up is uh Mr.
Bo. Uh we got uh Michael J. Bo coming
on. He's going to be talking about that
case where he's suing the military about
those um those Marines. Uh I I believe
they were killed uh because of this
whole situation with the these Afghanis
having sex with little boys over there.
We'll be right back after these
messages,
guys. And now a word from our sponsors.
Pacific West Bamboo, your premier source
for sustainable building material. They
provide construction grade and craft
grade bamboo material for all your
indoor, outdoor, and gardening needs.
Uh, contact them for event planning and
display building as well,
5038398126. Or you go to their new
website, Pacific
Westbamboo.com. Or you can contact them
on Facebook at Pacific Westbamboo.
That's
5038398126. Amanda from Pacific West
Bamboo was our first sponsor. Uh she's
been so good to us. Uh so please support
her in return. I want to make everybody
aware of our new member section at
www.opermanreport.com. Uh you can go
there and sign up for our monthly,
quarterly, or yearly
subscription. You can even purchase
episodes one by one. uh you get full
access to brand new original content,
new guests, new uncensored interviews,
my own investigations and reports, and
we're going to be adding uh sections
with documents, images, police reports,
uh either provided by myself or by my
guests or for my own investigations, my
own reports. Uh so you can go to
opermanreport.com and you can sign up
there tonight. You can start listening
tonight. Straw Man, I want to mention
Straw Man. Straw Man is a band uh out of
Toronto, Canada. Uh they're good friends
at the Operant Report. Uh they're a trio
of guys who share the same mindset uh
most of us here do and they put that
energy into their words and music. Uh so
check them out at the
strawmanusic.com and drop them a line uh
to let them know that you heard them
here on the Arman Report. Uh we'll be
doing an interview with Shawn Duffy
soon.
You can get an autographed copy of my
book, How to Succeed as a Private
Investigator, by visiting my PI website,
emailrevealer.com. We also offer a
computer and cell phone forensics. We
can recover deleted text messages to
uncover infidelity. Uh we can uh we
offer asset searches, locates, email
tracing, background reports, and we can
even trace your spouse's email address
back to internet dating websites to
catch them cheating online. You can
reach us at
800-572-9762 or you can email me at
emailrevealeraol.com. New World Mexican
Women. Everyone loves the New World
Mexican women and their their line of
fine handcrafted authentic Mexican
jewelry of stone mosaic and abilain
stone inlay. In their first book titled
New World Mexican Women, available on
lulu.com, uh they teach you how to make
this jewelry and they have a collection
of love letters to their men from their
hometown that have immigrated to the
United States to find work. Uh they have
also published a new book entitled
Aukina to the rodeo. It's about a young
girl that falls in love with a rodeo
bull rider and she runs away with him uh
without telling her family. You can find
the New World Mexican women by googling
New World Mexican women. And you can ask
them about uh their deals on
wholesaling, their fine jewelry, and all
of the other projects that they have
going on. Uh if you'd like to have your
business or website advertised here and
promoted all over the world on dozens of
stations every day, give us a call at
800572-9762 or email
opergmail.com. And now back to our show.
Okay, welcome back to the Operman
Report. I'm your host, private
investigator Ed Oppperman. Uh, show is
brought to you by emailrevealer.com. Hey
guys, uh, keep in mind good old our
buddy there, uh, uh, John Padesh, author
of Drugs Used as a Weapon Against Us and
this the FBI's war on Tupac. Uh he'll be
doing a slideshow presentation of his
book at Loo De Jesus.
Um 400 PM to 7:00 p.m. Pacific Standard
Time Sunday night. This is going to be
in LA uh on 10:25 on Hollywood
Boulevard. And then at Isu Juan Books
uh on
10:28 between 7:00 and 8:30 p.m. and
this is off of Crunchaw Boulevard and uh
Lemur Park. So it's good old John Pod.
Uh right now I'm going to get a hold of
uh attorney famed attorney. This is a
really big shot. Uh Michael J. Bo and
we're going to be talking about the
American Marines. He's representing pro
bono these American Marines uh who I
believe were killed. uh he's
representing their parents because these
Marines were murdered
by these we get the story from from
attorney Michael J. Bo. It's an
incredible uh story here. Let's see if
we get a hold of him
here. Got a whole bunch of announcements
tonight after during the after show.
Oh boy, I hate when this
happens. Oh god. Wouldn't be the first
time.
Your call has been forwarded to an
automated voice messaging system.
Mike Bowie
is not available at the tone. Please
record your message. When you finished
recording up or press one for more
options to send a fax, press four now.
To leave a call back number, press five.
Hi, Mr. Bowie. How are you? It's Ed
Oper, host of the Oper Report. We're
live on the air right now and I'm trying
to get a hold of you uh so we could do
this show at 6 p.m. just like we had
discussed today. Uh, so I'm going to
call you back in a couple of seconds,
but if not, if you get this message,
call me back at
7026054894. That's
7026054894. Uh, as soon as I pick you
up, you're going to be live on the air.
Uh, the operant
report. Okay, let's give it one more try
and then uh I guess I'll just
uh Oh
boy. Try calling again here. And if not,
I'll just uh maybe take some phone calls
or
something. Was really excited about
covering this
topic with Michael J. Bowie, attorney at
law, New York City.
I'm a little worried that perhaps uh
uh he he thought I met 6:00 p p.m.
Eastern time, which is why I emailed him
a whole bunch of times to try and
clarify the time that we would be
having. Mr. Michael J. Buoie,
your call has been forwarded to an
automated voice messaging system. Well,
hopefully he'll call back. Okay. And
that's too bad because I got a whole
bunch of stuff that I want to cover in
the after
show. Well, isn't this just
fun? Okay. I guess we'll go straight
into the after
show. Uh, let me pull up my
notes. Well, let's just pretend this is
the after show.
Okay. And
uh I I'm going to start a new format to
the after show than what we've been
doing previously
uh for all these many two years. Uh and
I'm going to be starting off from now on
with an update on Mark Harris. Uh okay,
my new best friend. As a matter of fact,
good old Mark Harris. Who knows? He
could become my roommate. Uh who could
become my uh uh what do you call it?
like a a TV show like The Odd Couple.
You know, we may be doing a reality TV
show, me and Mark Harris. People who
don't know who Mark Harris
is. Uh you can look up uh in our
archives on Spreaker and YouTube. Uh I
did a show with Mark Harris. It's called
like Mark Harris. We talk about Trump
and uh I forget what else. A gay papa
for Trump is what it's called. Now, who
Mark Harris is, is
a he was a frequent
guest
on he's a frequent guest on the Howard
Stern show seven years ago. His last
appearance was seven years ago, but he
had a good 10 year stretch as a frequent
guest on Howard Stern. A real character.
He became famous because he married
Martha Ray. I guess he was like in his
40s. Yeah, about his 40s or 50s. He was
a gay man, but he married Martha Ray,
who was like 30 years older than him.
And she used to be an actress back in
the 40s and stuff like that. And it was
a what is it called? The USO troop uh
entertainer. And then she did that
uh in my time in my life. She became
famous because she did the uh a denture
commercial about dentures. She would
call I'm Martha Ray the big mouth and
then my for effort, you know, dental,
you know, cream or whatever it was, you
know. Yeah. Right. And I'm not calling
Mark right now. So I I met Mark Gray on
Facebook Mark Gray Mark uh Mark uh
Harris. I met Mark Harris on
Facebook. And uh what happened is uh I
saw his picture there and I knew who he
was. I'm not calling him right now. I
saw his picture. I knew who he was. Gay
Papa. You got to look up this song. Look
go to YouTube and look up I'm a gay
papa. Okay. He sings this song. He made
up these crazy words to it. So I see him
on Facebook. I said, "Let me add this
guy on." So I add him on, fine. You
know, there's no problems. But then he
sees me talking about Trump one night
and he decides to start heckling me on
Facebook that he's a Trump supporter and
all this kind of stuff. We get into this
big debate on Facebook. I invite him to
come on the show. We were supposed to do
one hour, a tight hour. You know how I'm
trying to edit these shows on the fly
and do all this, you know, so that I can
prepare these 1 hour shows. All these
stations I got to send all these shows
all over the place. So I try and edit it
during the show while I'm doing it. So I
want I need a solid hour from him. I
said, "Mark, we're going to do this
sharp one hour." You can't get him to
answer a question. You can't get it to
focus or whatever. He's going on and on
about all these crazy stories. You got
to look up the show. It's
hysterical. And then after the show, you
know, he's so excited. It's it's his
return to show business. He's got his
fans. He's doing all he's all excited.
He's doing all this stuff. He's a big
Trump supporter. Okay. And he was able
to get Trump to
uh what do you call it?
Um retweet a link to his show. Okay. But
he's a total character and he has not
left me alone one day. He's not given me
a day's piece since I met this
man. and he's the same person off the
air that he is on the air. You know,
he's these long stories and and these
long emails, you know, and he's a
lovable guy. He's very charismatic. He's
very likable and uh he's a sweet guy,
you know. He really is. As much as who
knows, God God only knows what's going
on in real life with this guy. And you
know, God only knows how long it's going
to be till I strangle this guy because,
you know, it's a very good chance. Uh so
this week my adventures with Mark
Harris is that uh he contacts me and
he's he doesn't know how to copy and
paste. Okay. So if you send him a link,
he doesn't know how to click on the
link. Okay. So what he does is he takes
the link and he writes it down longhand
and then he types it into his uh browser
later on. He writes it down and then he
types it in later. But he also doesn't
know that uh you can type in on his
keyboard a front slash. So when he's
typing in something, he doesn't put the
front slash in. He thinks he could just,
you know, skip it and just go on and go
on beyond the front slash and then not
put it in. Okay, this is what he thinks.
So it's it's hysterical. So I try to
send him the instructions on how to copy
and paste and he doesn't even he Okay, I
wrote it down. He says, I wrote down the
URL for you. Ah,
okay. But he can't go and visit the link
right now. Okay. Cuz he's so busy
answering all of his fan mail that he
gotten from our show. And also too that
he's he is guys in daily
communication with the Trump campaign.
He's emailing back and forth with them,
these long emails back and forth with
with the Trump. He has a contact over
there cuz he was able to get Trump to
retweet his YouTube channel, you know,
uh, and he was, you know, he's able to
do this. So, I don't know. Don't look at
me, okay? He's somehow uh able to pull
this
off. Uh, good old uh Mark Harris, but I
love him. Okay. Uh, and uh that's going
to be our new uh we're going to have to
do a a Mark Harris update at the
beginning of the after show uh every
week. Uh,
unless, my god, if uh
uh you know, if my guests don't show up
every week, you know what I mean? We
need the guests to show up. Uh I had a
feeling we're going to have a trouble
with Mr. Bowie. Uh because
uh it was difficult booking him and uh
going back and forth with him.
Um there is something
uh very very serious and you know I I
was hoping that we would have an after
show and that the title would be uh
about baby
Nicholas and uh that whole story. Okay,
because I I wanted a nice tight one-hour
show. The title would be about let's all
pray for baby Nicholas or let's all get
together to help baby
Nicholas. Okay. And now it looks like by
fortune or whatever that's going to be
impossible cuz it's looks like I'm going
to be talking for two hours straight.
I'll probably take some maybe we won't
do it after show or else I'll just take
some calls.
Um, this week for me,
uh, has been a difficult week to be a a
radio host, okay? To to be a private
investigator and a radio host. Uh, cuz,
uh, not even this week, the past couple
of weeks, because I've gotten a lot of
clients contacting me about really
interesting stuff that I'd like to talk
to you about on the air. Uh, I had this
one situation
with this woman uh and her story I I I
can't talk about that at all. Okay. But
uh her story and I'm hoping I can get a
release from her for the future. Uh
would make a an incredible feature film
and a book, you know, has everything in
it.
uh blackmail, uh criminal charges,
police corruption, government
corruption, uh all kinds of uh adultery
and infidelity. Uh all these uh
incredible facets to this story
uh in this woman and not just her life,
but her husband's life and his bosses
and his co-workers is they're all mixed
in here with this situation. And and
this is a situation where a client comes
to me cuz they're in big trouble and
they need my help to solve their
problem. And uh I believe that I was
very
successful in in not just helping this
woman and her immediate problem uh but
also problems that around them this
whole bunch uh that they were dealing
with. Okay. Okay. And I can't go into
any details on it, although it's a
fascinating story and I hope to get a
release from them in the future to
discuss this because it's just it's
probably one of the most incredible case
I've ever worked
on. So, there was that and it's been on
my mind a lot. It was on my mind last
weekend when we were doing the after
show last weekend.
Um, I got
another job in the past week or
so and this was a an asset
search. Okay. I got a call from a
private investigator in New York. Uh, he
didn't know about me in the radio show.
He didn't know I was from New York, but
he I have this reputation of doing
really good asset searches because a lot
of private investigators no longer do
them. Uh, because they had passed some
laws. Oh boy, it was a long time ago. U
back in the old days when you want to do
an asset search, it was really simple.
All you did was um you you'd find out
the target that you want to do the asset
search on. You get his social security
number, his name, his address,
information like that. You find all that
information first and then you just call
up his bank and say, "Hey, I'm this
guy." You make believe you're the guy.
And they say, "Well, what's the last
word of social security?" "Well, it's
this." "Well, where do you live?" "Well,
I live here." you know, you do all that
and then they send you the information,
but then they passed these laws. It was
called the Graham Bllye laws, uh,
privacy banking privacy act, you know,
uh, that made doing that, pretexting.
They made that
illegal. And then the first guy they
busted doing it was a friend of mine,
uh, Victor, uh, from, uh, Staten Island,
uh, buddy of mine in, and they destroyed
him. Uh, they they contacted him. This
woman contacted him. says, "Hey, I'm
about to get married. I'm a little
suspicious about my fiance. I think he
might have financial problems. Can you
help me out? Can you do a background uh
asset search on him?" And he did it and
they caught him and they arrested him. I
don't know if they arrested him or sued
him. It was like the FTC went after him
or something like that. And uh he had to
pay like this huge fine. He had to pay
back all the money he ever made at his
business. And then they shut him down
and he moved upstate New York and he was
a destroyed man, you know, just over
just for doing work that people think is
normal that private investigators can
do. So most investigators have stopped
doing asset searches because they
they're all afraid of that law that
you're not allowed to do that. I don't
do it that way. You don't have to do it
that way. Uh if someone comes to me and
they want to order an asset search, I go
to my sources. I have two or three
different sources. You need need
different parts of an asset search to
find bank accounts to find uh uh oh
property records and uh um whatever
those things are corporations, you know,
and you order this information up and
sometimes sometimes you have accounts
with with companies, you can just do it
automatically online and you find all
this stuff. You order the paperwork to
come in uh uh public records and
stuff and you go to these different
areas, you find this information, you
pull it up and then you get it and you
put together the report and you send it
back. You know, this that's the fun
exciting work of a private investigator
that most people think that, oh boy, I'd
love to be a private investigator. Oh,
what? What? Cuz you know, you got to do
this kind of work. It's boring, you
know. And then you'll also hear people
talking about they'll say uh oh I'd make
a great private investigator because uh
I'm psychic you know and I have
intuition. I have a great intuition and
I'm great at figuring things out and you
and uh they think that that's what a
private investigator does. Uh but it
it's really not. Okay. It's a lot of
mundane humrum stuff. Uh but also too
I'm getting back to the situation here
again. I have a whole theme when I'm
getting out here to you is it's about
solving people's problems. people coming
to me with their problems and I I go in
there and I solve their problem. Now,
this case started off as an asset
search. This PI from New York contacts
me, gives me this information, I put the
orders out, blah blah blah. When the
paperwork starts coming back to me and
I'm looking through it to put together
my report, I see that I know these
people. I know the people that I'm
investigating, right? Cuz I a very
common name. They were from Staten
Island and it was very common name. But
then when I saw a couple of businesses
they were involved in then right away I
knew exactly who these people were and
people always laugh you know it's this
big joke with me is that every guest I
have on I know every show I you know
they mention name I know oh yeah I know
they start talking about Eddie knows
everybody right it's a big joke
everybody loves to make fun of me okay
fine I can put up with your abuse
um so I
see the names in this report that I'm
about to prepare that I know them right
now. The ethical thing to do, the proper
thing to do is to um and now I have to
reveal this to the person that hired me.
Okay? I have to reveal to them uh that
uh I know the subject of the
investigation. I have a personal
relationship with them. And then he has,
you know, which is what I would want,
you know, if I hire somebody to
investigate and they know the person.
And I want to find I want to know that
right
away. So I contact this guy in New York
and I says, "Hey, you know, I know these
people. In fact, I know them very very
well. I know their their family. You
know, they I I know this one of these
people. I went to high school with them.
I know him from from childhood. He has
had dinner at my house. I've had dinner
at his house. I know his mother. I know
his father. You know, I really know
these people, you
know. So,
uh you know, I got to reveal that to
him.
Oh, by the way, too, all this is off the
clock, too. I'm not even getting paid
for any of this time now. It's all extra
time, you know. Uh it's not a flat fee
uh job. Now, I'm putting in extra
work. So, we we chat about this and you
know, and I find out, you know, well,
what's this case all about? So, and and
I find out it's
a it involves a dispute between family
members and he's working for an
attorney. Okay. So it turns out he
mentions the name of the attorney. I
know the attorney as well too from
Staten Island. So I explain to him I
know the attorney as well. Fine. Okay.
He puts me in touch with the attorney. I
talk to him. He's feeling me out too,
you know, cuz cuz what happens is too,
especially in a small town like Staten
Island. Uh like if you if you had a case
in Staten Island, you have hire a
private investigator and he knows the
other people, he could turn on you and
work undercover for the other side.
Okay, that stuff happens in real life.
Okay. For unethical people, you know,
but I try and really really avoid any
kind of problems or any kind of uh uh
questioning of my uh uh honesty and
integrity. So I talked to him, he
explains to me what the problem is and I
said to him, "Okay, I know all these
people. I know both sides, okay? And
they've known me my whole life, okay?
And this lawyer knew me my whole life,
too. And when I say that kind of thing,
I haven't always been in the PI
business. I've been in other business. I
was in the nightclub business. I was uh
in the
um other kinds of businesses and stuff.
So people know me on Staten Island, have
a reputation over there. And I had a
reputation of having influence with
these people.
So we all agreed I was going to try to
negotiate a settlement with all these
family members and solve the
situation. So I went in again. I'm still
off the clock. Okay. We agreed I was
going to go in there and try to give
this a shot.
So, I
did I I was able to contact first, you
know, because you can pretty much find
anybody and I had a lot of information.
I I was able to contact the kid I went
to high school with, you know, and and
the problems was with his uncles and his
parents and stuff like that. And I I was
able to contact him first. And then he
put me in touch with his dad and they
put me in touch with the uncle. And I
was able to to negotiate a fair
settlement between all these parties and
solve their problems without causing
them a ton of money uh going through
court and going through litigation and
and causing all this uh animosity and
hatred within the family. I was able to
take this situation and solve that
problem in a way that no one had dreamed
would be possible at the time when this
family hired this lawyer and he hired
this investigator to do the litig the
preparation for the litigation and and
he hired me to do this asset search.
Okay. And and that's pretty much how I
live my life. Okay, as far as my
business life in the in the PI world,
you know, I get mixed up in these
frequent cases, you know, and
uh things kind of take on a life of
their own and then next thing you know,
I'm I'm preparing an exhibit for
congressional investigation. You know,
people ask me, "How do you get involved
in this stuff?" And that's kind of how
these things happen.
I I also use this uh this kind
of leads into my interviewing style with
these guests, okay? Which which so I
bring that PI experience to to the radio
show and how I interview these guests.
And uh in the past couple of months,
we've had this this thing where people
are saying, "Well, Ed, you're not asking
tough questions." Okay.
Uh you you got to understand I've
interviewed thousands of
people as a private investigator and my
job is to get a statement from them.
Okay? It's not really to to get them to
say what I want them to say.
Um, and some people your idea of asking
a tough question is not asking a tough
question. It's asking a rude question or
an angry question or an insulting
question, which if you do that in any
interview, whether it's as a private
investigator or on the radio, all you're
going to do is you're putting you're
building up walls and defenses. Uh,
you're you're the person you're
interviewing is going to put up a wall
and be defensive and he's going to shut
down and maybe just hang up on me. This
is, you know, this is long distance.
It's not like I'm sitting in somebody's
office or somebody's home interviewing
them. You know, you can kind of, you
know, you don't get, you know, they kick
you out, you don't get up. You just sit
there and keep talking. You know, it's
not like that. You know, this is I'm not
pissing anybody. Uh this is
a if there's a difference
between I do ask tus tough questions and
I would invite you to go back to the
interview with
um uh the FBI director Richard Lambert
who was in charge of the anthrax
investigation and this guy's an
attorney. This guy's also an
investigator. He's interviewed many many
people. Okay. Uh, and
um, if you listen to him when I was
interviewing him, this this guy didn't
there was a lot of things he didn't want
to answer. And if you listen to him, I
boxed him in, okay? When you hear me
giving these long questions like last
week with Vince Font, and uh, I say to
him, uh, okay, Vince, you know, your guy
there, he's out in the woods for 30
days. He hasn't combed his hair, he
hasn't brushed his teeth, he has no
toilet paper, he hasn't washed his hands
or his face. You know, they may he may
you say he's eating and then drinking
from the the streams and stuff like
that, but you're trying to tell me that
when he got out of there, he
hitchhikes and someone picks him up.
Okay. You know, Vince Fon's a nice guy,
but uh even he couldn't say, "Hey,
you're right. That sounds, you know,
kind of winky. What happened there?" You
know, so there's a way to ask these
questions without screaming at the
person uh and u being rude to them,
okay? Because we want to get a statement
from them. and we want to get them on
the record and that's what my role is
here. And I would invite you to go back
to listen to the Richard Lampard
interview and if you hear him when I'm
boxing now I'm I was working that night
guys, okay? And if you listen to the
interview, I'm boxing him in. This guy's
an attorney and I'm boxing him in with
these questions and he's
going, okay, because he knows I'm boxing
him in and he knows these are tough
questions. So there's a lot of
difference between asking asking tough
questions. And I think a lot of people
can see what I'm doing, okay? And uh and
not uh and just asking angry questions
and yelling at people uh which you're
not going to get here. I have no I'm not
out to make the whole world agree with
me and make the whole world uh agree
with my opinions. Okay. Now, we're going
to take a commercial break. And when I
get back from this commercial break, the
the reason why I'm bringing all this up
about my PI career and my my
my problem solving uh abilities is cuz I
need you all to to come together with me
and help me to solve a huge problem
right now. It's the biggest problem
that's on my heart right now in my life.
And I'm begging you all to to come with
me and work on me, work on this with me
together. Uh so we'll be taking these
messages. And yes, the New World Mexican
women are still sponsors. I love them.
Uh oh, by the way, before I get to that
uh the message about the New World
Mexican women, I cannot believe I'm
going to have to talk another 90
minutes. I cannot do this. I quit.
Not only are the New World Mexican women
uh beautiful people and I love them so
much you have no
idea is that
um they want to support the show as much
as they can and they have all this
jewelry that they want to send me to
sell and they say like retail I can sell
for like $1,000. So, if there's someone
out there that can do something with
this and help me sell this jewelry
because we we got to get this show uh
onto the these AM stations and all in
order to build up the member section.
There's a lot going on here, guys,
behind the scenes. Uh so, we're going to
take a commercial break here. The New
World Mexican Women. We're going to talk
about John Padesh. Then, when we get
back, I'm going to beg of
you. We're going to we're going to
you're going to help me solve the
biggest problem that I'm facing right
now in my life. Uh we'll be right back
after these
messages. And now a word from our
sponsors. Pacific West Bamboo, your
premier source for sustainable building
material. They provide construction
grade and craft grade bamboo material
for all your indoor, outdoor, and
gardening needs. Uh contact them for
event planning and display building as
well.
5038398126 or you go to their new
website pacific
westbamboo.com or you can contact them
on Facebook at Pacific Westbamboo.
That's
5038398126. Amanda from Pacific West
Bamboo was our first sponsor. Uh she's
been so good to us. Uh so please support
her in return. I want to make everybody
aware of our new member section at
www.opermanreport.com.
operandreport.com. Uh you can go there
and sign up for a monthly, quarterly, or
yearly subscription. You can even
purchase episodes one by one. Uh you get
full access to brand new original
content, new guests, new uncensored
interviews, my own investigations and
reports, and we're going to be adding uh
sections with documents, images, police
reports uh either provided by myself or
by my guests or for my own
investigations, my own reports. Uh, so
you can go to
operandmanreport.com and you can sign up
there tonight. You can start listening
tonight. Straw Man. I want to mention
Straw Man. Straw Man is a band uh out of
Toronto, Canada. Uh, they're good
friends at the Operant Report. Uh,
they're a trio of guys who share the
same mindset uh most of us here do, and
they put that energy into their words
and music. Uh, so check them out at
strawmanmusic.com and drop him a line uh
to let them know that you heard him here
on the Opman Report. Uh, we'll be doing
an interview with Shawn Duffy
soon. You can get an autographed copy of
my book, How to Succeed as a Private
Investigator, by visiting my PI website,
emailrevealer.com. We also offer a
computer and cell phone forensics. We
can recover deleted text messages to
uncover infidelity. Uh we can uh we
offer asset searches, locates, email
tracing, background reports, and we can
even trace your spouse's email address
back to internet dating websites to
catch them cheating online. You can
reach us at
800572-9762 or you can email me at email
revealerol.com. New World Mexican Women.
Everyone loves the New World Mexican
women and their their line of fine
handcrafted authentic Mexican jewelry of
stone mosaic and abilain stone inlay. In
their first book titled New World
Mexican Women available on Lulu.com, uh
they teach you how to make this jewelry
and they have a collection of love
letters to their men from their hometown
that have immigrated to the United
States to find work. Uh they have also
published a new book entitled Azukina to
the rodeo. It's about a young girl that
falls in love with a rodeo bull rider
and she runs away with him uh without
telling her family. You can find the New
World Mexican women by googling New
World Mexican women. And you can ask
them about uh their deals on wholesaling
their fine jewelry and all of the other
projects that they have going on. Uh if
you'd like to have your business or
website advertised here and promoted all
over the world on dozens of stations
every day, give us a call at
800572-9762 or email
opermanreportgmail.com. And now back to
our show.
Okay, welcome back to the Opperman
Report. I am your host, private
investigator Ed
Obererman. Don't forget the show is
brought to you by email
reviewer.com. Okay, so
now the story I'm about to tell you,
okay, deserves its own show. And uh I'm
trying to get these people to come on
the show as a guest and tell this story
to you, but that's a problem in
itself.
Um little Nicholas is his little
baby. Uh right now he's being raised by
his grandmother who's my age. Okay. Uh,
as a matter of fact, his
grandmother is a woman that I've known
uh, let's see, I've known her since I
was 15 years
old. So, it's been a long time without
giving my age. Okay. Uh, I met her for
the first time on Staten Island.
Uh, I no, I was
16 and she was
15. I set my eyes on this woman. I fell
in love with her. She's the most
beautiful woman I've ever seen in my
life. And uh the first thing I did was I
asked, "Well, how old are you?" And she
told me she was
19. She lied about her age. Okay? So I
fig this this girl's not going to want
anything to do with me. She's I'm only
16. She's 19. But she lied. She was only
15. Okay.
Uh then
um she married a she married the the the
grandson of my landlord, my parents
landlord in his house on Staten Island
and Annie wound up coming to live
upstairs from my parents house because
you know they were renting the house
above from my parents house. It was a
two family house on Staten Island just
like you know that movie two family
house on Staten Island with all the guys
from Sopranos. It was just like that
kind of house uh in the Annadale section
of Staten Island. So we all grew up
together as kids.
And uh she married this guy. They had
two little kids. And uh my mother used
to babysit for these kids, you know, her
daughter uh and her son. And uh you
know, time went on and uh well, you
know, things happen in life and you
know, she divorced this guy and uh me
and this woman started dating, you know,
back and forth. You know, this wild
uh love affair that went on across the
country. That's how I wound up in Vegas
cuz she had moved to Vegas. And I came
out here to go see her, you know, and
you know, we broke up. We would break up
and fight and stuff like that and get
back together again. And uh it's really
a funny story cuz
uh we had broken up at this one point
and I was in uh California on I was
standing on the Sunset Strip in
California and
uh so me we had broken up and she went
and called up my answering machine and
she broke the code on my answer machine
and she changed the outgoing message and
it says Eddie's a real loser. Don't date
him. So when you call to leave me a
message, you heard her voice saying
don't date me. And so I had met this
really cool girl in in the Sunset Strip
and but I gave my phone number, you
know, and she called up the number.
Who's what's that voice on your answer
machine? It was this crazy nut. So,
okay. So, you know, back and forth, we
broke up, got back together again, all
this kind of stuff,
right? So, she has these two kids and uh
her daughter, and by the way, too, these
two kids were the love of my life. I
love these kids. You know, these were
the first real kids that I raised. You
know, everybody knows about my
relationship with my daughter. I've had
a lot of girlfriends with kids. I raised
a lot of kids in my life. I took in a a
runaway kid off the street and when I
first got saved, let him stay with
me. Uh just, you
know, raised a whole bunch of kids. I
was a uh what do you call it? The
assistant youth pastor at our church in
Staten Island. So, but I I I love this
woman's kids. I was very close to them
and we still are close. Uh but her
daughter became uh an addict, a drug
addict, and she became addicted to uh
first
methamphetamine and now
heroin. So
uh she was addicted so bad that uh my
friend got custody of her
daughter and you know she'd gotten
clean, she'd gotten off it, you know,
rehab rehab since she was 15 years old,
you know, over and over, you know.
And uh now she's really bad on on heroin
right now. And uh while she was
pregnant, you know, she had this little
baby, Nicholas, and I guess she was on
heroin and meth and stuff like that when
she gave birth. So he was
a an ultra preey.
and
uh foster care or CPS or whoever these
people are go into the hospital and they
take custody of this little baby
Nicholas and they tell her, "Well, you
can't have this baby and they put the
baby into foster
care." I I need you guys to really pay
attention to this because this this is a
miracle baby. This is not your average
story.
when this little baby was in foster
care, there was something going on. My
friend knew that something he wasn't
growing right. He wasn't things weren't
right in this foster
home. And what ultimately happened was
is that the foster
father killed
himself and murdered a foster baby
little girl that was Nicholas's little
foster sister.
practically in the same crib. They were
lying, you know, for whatever reason,
this guy killed himself and he killed a
little baby girl and he didn't kill
Nicholas.
So, whatever happened with that, God
only
knows. But this little baby was spared,
you know, and uh oh my god, I met him
the first time. Uh it was about a year
ago when Victoria remember when Victoria
was going out on her first date with
that
boy and uh you know we needed a a woman
to you know teach her how to do her
makeup and do her hair and stuff like
that for this little date you know
little boy
Gonzalo. I hardly even spoke English
before little Mexican kid that she
befriended you know. So I took Victoria
over to my friend's house and she did
her makeup. you know, I did way too much
makeup and stuff like that. I would look
terrible, but you know, we left, you
know, being nice. And so, while they
were up there doing the makeup and the
hair and stuff like that, I was
downstairs taking care of little baby
Nicholas who was survived, you know, a
murder of his uh his uh
sister. I've had a lot of babies, you
know, a lot of kids around me and stuff
like that. And um he was a year
old, couldn't crawl, couldn't sit up,
couldn't sit up by himself, you know,
wasn't
talking, but he has this little smile.
There's a picture of him on my Facebook,
and I'll have a picture of him up on the
blog. Okay, he's doing a lot better now.
He's about two years old now. He's
running around. He walks. I only seen I
haven't seen him in person. I only see
him in pictures.
This
week he's been
diagnosed with
cranio.
Okay. So, he's going to need brain
surgery
now. Something about the brain doesn't
detach from the skull or something. I
don't even know what this
is.
Okay, guys. The story's not over. This
doesn't get better.
The mother is raising a six-year-old
sister. She's raising the
granddaughter. Now she's raising this
little boy here and he needs constant
medical attention, constant medical uh
appointments. Uh plus just regular baby
stuff, just regular trying to take care
of a baby and to raise two little kids
when you're our age. You know, the kind
of lives we've
lived, this woman has no
car. This woman has no
income. She's living with her
mother or her mother's social security
and her mother's retirement
money. You
know, this family has no help. No one is
helping them. I talked to by by the way
my friend won't come on the show because
he's afraid of CPS is because because
CPS is covering up this murder suicide
with this other kid you know trying to
say that there was nothing suspicious or
weird going on
here. So I can't say her name on the
air. She won't come on the air. She's
afraid to come on. She's afraid to do a
GoFundMe. We had a little GoFundMe going
on there for a little
while, but she's afraid to ask for
help because we know what
happens, you know, when when you become
an enemy of CPS.
whatever little assistance they're
getting, a food stamp card or whatever
it
is, is nothing compared to the help that
they need. Okay, like I said, they have
no car. They they live in Vegas, you
need a car no matter what. They live all
the way out northwest, you know, where
there's nothing out there. I don't even
know why anybody moves there.
There has to be
uh some kind of
sanity in this
situation where we have all this money
to these stupid Benghazi hearings, $5
million for that to to you know the wars
all over the place. We could do all this
stuff. Throw people in jail, court
trials. We're throwing this guy my free
guys. We're throwing him in prison for
three years. Court trials and go after
him.
But here we have a situation where a
little baby is a miracle baby man
fighter man. He's surviving. How's he
doing it? You know sister's killed right
next to
him. But this kid survived and but and
this family needs help.
Now I don't know. There is no
fundraiser. This is what I'm trying to
tell you. I can't even tell you to send
money. I don't know where to send money
to. I don't know what to do with if the
solution but the solution is not just
raising money. They need local help here
in Nevada, in Las Vegas. They need
volunteers to come out to their home and
help them give them rides, to help them
with to clean their home, to cook meals,
to to change diapers, this kind of
stuff, you
know. And there's all these groups, man,
you know, with the with the the
anti-abortion groups and, you
know, you know, there must
be some resource out there for this
family. Okay, that I cannot think of
any people more worthy of our help and
our prayers u and and government
resources. God forbid that the
government would step in and help these
people instead of being afraid of the
government. So this is my
frustration, okay? When I wake up every
day, I get phone calls from people in
trouble. you know, hopefully they can
they can afford to hire me, you know,
and then I can come up with a plan to
try and solve their problems and get
them out of trouble. Okay? So, the
hurdle number one is first they got to
be able to pay me and then then then I
come up with a plan. The plan's either
going to work or it's not going to work.
Okay? But we're we got to do something,
right? You got to try. The frustration I
have here right now is here I have a
problem that's on my heart.
Seriously, in a major way. And this
family needs help. They are deserving of
help. And I know people, man, I know
that I can tell you about some people,
right? I know this woman. She has these
three kids. I don't know what the kids
have. It's a cerebal pausy or something
like that. I don't know what it is, but
these are functioning kids, man. These
they go to school. They're in the church
choir. They're all, you know, these are
high functioning kids. She gets, I
think, $1,500 for every one of these
kids every month. Plus, she gets someone
comes in and folds her laundry. This
woman doesn't even do anything. Her
mother takes care of these kids. She's
running off on vacation all over the
place.
There's people out there gaming the
system, you know, and when here's this
other family seriously needs help right
away. Now, they got some kind of uh food
stamps. I know they have that. Who knows
what else to get, but the you know, the
the the pittance, you know.
Uh,
so it I I'm getting a lot of messages in
in the chat room
uh people saying
uh you know what's the address? Where do
we mail money to? Do we got this? We
have to we have to come up with a plan.
We need an an organizing committee here
to come up with a plan for this family
to really raise money for them to go to
Finley Dodge and Finley Toyota, these
big car dealerships and uh these big
charity organizations, you know, and and
volunteers and and get
uh you know, volunteers to come and
help. One one thing I have in
mind, sorry. One thing I have in mind
here, do we still have dead air or can
you hear
me? Uh, one thing I have in mind is that
uh
Vic and her uh youth groups, these
church youth groups can make a project
of of going over there and taking turns
and helping to babysit and help to
change diapers and help to do laundry
and that kind of stuff because that's
what they seriously need.
Um, I hope I'm not frozen up here. And
uh, okay, good. You can't hear me. Okay,
so that's the baby Nicholas situation.
Okay. And, uh, we are going to need
funds, you know. Well, we are going to
need to raise money, but what we really
need to do is it's is to come up with a
a like a Ronald McDonald House or
something like that. You know, we we
need like a real thing here to come in
here and swoop in because I'm telling
you, I'm doing this show tonight without
a guest to to describe this Nicholas
situation because the grandmother who's
raising these kids doesn't have time to
to eat, to make a sandwich, to take a
shower, to to function in life. She
doesn't have time to sit on and when she
does get on the phone, she's lost her
voice. She can't even talk.
Okay, this is a dire drastic situation,
guys, that uh is beyond my abilities to
solve. Now, I know I've come on here
before and I've talked about problems,
okay? I came on with my my divorce
stuff, my custody stuff, but let's take
a look back at that. I solved that
problem, okay? You know, we could not
have come out of that any better than
than we have, okay? You know, I I took
care of that problem, guys. You know, so
I I can solve problems. uh you know we
did that all right and thank you all for
praying for me and helping all the help
you know guys helping out thank you all
okay and we have some steps ahead of
this we're going to get rid of that
judge we're going to put a new judge in
okay coming up next election so I'm very
frustrated about this cuz I you know
what am I going to do I got to work on
this show right I got you know cuz
people the memberships are dropping off
like crazy all right uh we got a huge
show coming up this weekend with these
two big guests and hopefully the members
section will will pick back up again.
Oh, by the way, too, I'll give you guys
a deal, too. If you want to sign up with
a member, a yearly membership, I'll do
it for 60 bucks, okay? Just put in a
PayPal and then send me an email and I
I'll give you a year subscription. Okay?
That's not that's savings of 15 bucks.
Okay? I only need about three or four of
those to get through the
week.
But yeah, right. We need a long-term
plan in here. I need people to help me
to contact all these churches in the
area cuz all these churches have youth
groups. They all have little teenage
girl youth groups that would this is
perfect for them. There's all these
groups about these anti-abortion groups,
you know, that that help women not to
get abortions, you know, and they're all
loving them and helping them. Okay.
Well, now we have a situation after, you
know, now we have a baby that's born.
Okay. You love that baby and a fetus.
Here's one for you now. That's a cute
kid, too. You can talk to him. You can
play with him. So, we need these groups.
So, I need people to help me to contact
these uh
um uh no, I need you to help contact
local churches in our neighborhood here
and these Save the Children type groups
or Ronald McDonald House, whatever you
can do. Okay? We're not going to come up
with a solution to this right now
tonight live on the air, but you can
start emailing me if you're if you're
interested in volunteering and working
for this kid. And when you see his
picture, he's an adorable
kid. Okay?
We're going to need your help with this.
All right, guys. And um well, I guess
we'll set up a GoFundMe without telling
her, but I would really appreciate if
someone else was in control of the money
and all that stuff like that and wasn't
me and I wasn't co-mingling with my
PayPal account with the business here
and with the radio show cuz it's just
not good.
Okay.
So, that's the situation and and and I'm
trying to to explain to you. I hope I I
made myself clear that that's why I
brought up the whole thing about me
solving problems as a PI and you know,
my experience and and how now I I need
your help to solve this problem because
I know that I can't do this on my own.
Okay? And really, it's the most
important thing I'm dealing with in my
life right now.
uh you know these are people I love
these people I care for care for all of
them you know long history with these
people and
um so I'm reaching out to you the
audience here to help us out with this
and uh to email me at
operanreportgmail.com if
uh you know you can help contact
charities and stuff like that see I I'm
I can't believe that we wouldn't be able
to go to a big automobile dealership
like Finley Dodge or Finley Toyota and
explain to them what the problem is
here. You know, I'll give them press.
I'll give them free ads on the show and
then they donate a car, you know, and uh
merry maids, you know, or or some kind
of maid service, you know, that wouldn't
chip in and, you know, help out, you
know, once a month, you know.
So
anyway, that's the situation with baby
Nicholas. This kid's a miracle. And uh
and like I said, there's a lot of people
out there that uh that do get help and
uh maybe don't deserve it. And uh here's
these people that that really really do
deserve it.
Now, you know what? If we want to take
if anybody wants to call in with
ideas or suggestions about how to help
baby Nicholas, uh, give me a call real
quick.
7026054894. Okay. Let's see
here. All right. Okay. I got your
message, Jessica. I'll give you the
address. Okay. Relax. You don't have to
contact me. You can email me tomorrow.
Give me the address tomorrow. Do you
need it tonight? What do you got? What
do you got? 24-hour post office episode
there. Hey
guys, I love you guys. Okay, the the
radio audience, you guys have no idea
how great you people are uh and how
funny you
are. It's just crazy. And we're all the
same kind of people. It's amazing. We're
all the same kind of people. Uh because,
you know, we pick up a lot of new
stations every week. And so, uh you
know, new listeners who never heard the
show before. Uh but it's always the same
kind of personality, the same kind of
attitude. Uh you know, uh real scrappy
kind of fighters, you know, who don't
want to take no for an answer and uh you
know, love these kind of stories. They
want to see justice. You know, I tell
you another funny thing, too, is
uh this is really crazy is with the
Twitter because we had um I used to have
an old Twitter account for my business.
It was called email revealer. So, I used
that for the the show.
But six, seven months ago, we set up a
new Twitter account called Operan Report
just for the show, for people listen to
the show. And we set that up and uh so
now it's all brand new people, only
people that that come to me from the
show. So there's only like 185 something
like that. There's like 85 people on
there, 90 people, right? But if you go
on there, they're
everyone, all my Twitter friends, okay,
they're either ex CIA agents, they're ex
they're exconvicts. I got the guy, you
know, Christopher Boyce, the Falcon of
the Snowman. He's I'm tweeting back and
forth to him the other day. It was like,
you know, my my Twitter, it's like a uh
the Star Wars bar, you know, something
crazy like that. I got the craziest
people. They're all pretty famous
people, too, man. A lot of really cool
people in my Twitter, man, let me tell
you. So, we're we're creating a great
community on there with a bunch of uh
renegade exmugglers and ex CIA agents
and uh excons, you know. Ah, my god.
Okay, we're down to about two minutes.
Um, and then we're going to do an after
show, I guess, right? Who cares? I'll
just keep talking here till I drop
dead and then maybe my insurance policy
can go to little baby Nicholas. I want
to say good night to the guys over at
Wake at Awake. Um, there seems to be a
little shakeup going on over there right
now. Uh, one of the guys who's been
running things, uh, is retiring. Uh,
Allan, God bless you, man. We love you.
Thank you for all your help. And, uh, a
lot of people getting burnt
out over at Wake Radio. So, if you tune
in normally to a Wake Radio and it's not
there in a couple weeks, just come
looking for me. I'm all over the place.
Uh, just Google uh, Operan Report. I
want to say good night to uh uh Angel
over at PSN.
Uh sorry, I went over a couple weeks ago
on the time. Uh so next week, uh I think
I don't I don't know if I have guest
booked for next week or not, but we got
a lot of big stuff coming up. You know
that. Uh same at bat time, same bat
channel. All right, guys. Good night
over at Awake and good night. No, no,
good night at PSN. We're saying good
night to you. U and we'll see you next
week.
And uh rest of you guys, I'm going to
play a
commercial and then we'll restart the uh
the show. The restart the speaker. Um so
everybody who was in speaker right now,
we're going to restart because I never
give up. I never stop.
Okay. Oh boy. Word from our sponsor.